AIDAN LEGASPI

FRONT END SOFTWARE ENGINEER

■ aidanlegaspi1@gmail.com

www.aidanlegaspi.com

619.253.1280

♀ San Francisco Bay Area

in /in/aidan-legaspi

• legaspi21

I'm a voracious learner with a passion for collaboration, creative expression and syntactic sugar. I love programming and keep a special place in my heart for Ruby and Javascript. I have worked as an Audio Engineer for 10 years in the music industry and now apply my pattern-recognition, musical algorithm composition, and strong communication skills to creating seamless user experiences by integrating a variety of Javascript libraries/frameworks and modern web technologies into full stack applications.

Skills

LANGUAGES

JavaScript

Ruby

HTML5

CSS3

FS6

FRAMEWORKS AND LIBRARIES

Ruby on Rails

React.js

React Native

Redux

jQuery

Sinatra

DATABASES

PostgreSQL

SQLite3

Firebase

TESTING

RSpec

Jasmine

mocha.js

TOOLS

Travis CI

Git

Adobe Photoshop

Sketch

Education

Dev Bootcamp

19 Week Immersive Full Stack Web Development Academy

Over 1000 hours of instruction and pair programming with TDD in an Agile environment.

Udemv

4 certifications | HTML5/CSS3 with Responsive Design | Javascript | React with Redux | React Native

LinkedIn Learning

3 certifications | RESTful Web API Design with Node.js | User Experience for Web Designers | JavaScript and AJAX

Southwestern College

Business Administration / Recording Arts and Technologies

Experience

TKO Video Communications

Front End Developer - Contract

San Jose Apr 2017 to Current

- Modernized video conferencing portal for Realtor.com's all hands meetings in Javascript, HTML and CSS.
- Reporting directly to the CEO as the sole developer responsible for UI components and third party software integrations.
- Designed and implemented web conferencing portals in production for Realtor.com, LYTX, Big Fish Games & Harry Markowitz.
- Ensured cross-browser compatibility.

Dev Bootcamp

Full Stack Web Developer

Iul 2016 to Dec 2016

- Dev Bootcamp is a 19-week intensive training program for aspiring web developers, specializing in Ruby on Rails, HTML5, CSS, Test Driven Development, Object-Oriented Javascript (AJAX, jQuery), Git for Version Control, Linux and Command Line Client, MVC design architecture and Agile Development.
- Graduated from the program in December 2016.
- In addition, this program encourages and fosters team work in a high paced learning environment

Fetty Music

Freelance Audio Engineer/ Producer

2006 to 2016

- Composed original music for Gucci Mane, Yg, Jim Jones and Yung Joc.
- Conducted marketing campaigns amassing over 5 million total YouTube views on Music Videos and Audio.
- Distributed independent music on iTunes, Amazon, Spotify, Pandora and all other major music streaming and distribution platforms.
- Produced "Thinking of You" currently at 2,796,122 YouTube views, over 50k in sales and over \$4k in YouTube revenue.
- Spearheaded a campaign for an unknown artist resulting in the release of 7 videos, 118k views and 4000% viewership increase in 1 year.
- Signed a distribution deal with Empire records to distribute music worldwide on all digital platforms including iTunes, Amazon, Spotify, Pandora.
- Produced 'Symphony' record and collected over 400k YouTube views.
- Executed a viral marketing campaign securing placement on a YouTube channel with 11.5 million subscribers.

Projects

Taco

Taco is an on-demand delivery service that lets you order and share tacos with friends.

- + Mobile app for iOS and Android built with React Native, Redux, Firebase for user authentication and React-Native-Router-Flux.
- + Designed UI/UX for all mobile views using custom and open source components .
- + Wireframe of application using Balsamiq.
- + Decoupled architecture consumes custom API.

Taco-AP

REST API built to provide data to the Taco native and web application.

- + Test Driven Development with RSPEC and HTTPIE for manually testing requests. + Deployed with Heroku using Travis for continuous integration.
- + Open sourced on GitHub with endpoint documentation.

Butter Lovers

For the film buff in everyone. Butter Lovers allows users to join the discussion with qualified critics and rate nostalgic films.

- $+ \\ Implemented a search \\ algorithm for films \\ by \\ title \\ and \\ by \\ category \\ using \\ SQL/Active \\ record \\ queries. \\$
- + Designed website layout and UX flows to provide user account interaction, display most popular films and latest user reviews.
- + Consumed OMDB API to populate PostgreSQL database with film data on 300 films

See Food

Ever wanted to find restaurants by the food you crave? This app integrates APIs to help you find your next meal.

- + Developed 15 React components that asynchronously fetch and display data from a backend Rails API.
- + Led development team of 4 using SCRUM/Agile methodology.
- + Integrated full user authentication w/ BCrypt.

Score Placements

A RESTful app that helps music producers land artist placements by creating a community where producers can select which artists they want to work with and the artists can select from curated music.

- + Displays tweets from artists and industry personnel with over 30k followers and an email address.
- + Written in Ruby using Sinatra framework.
- + Consumes Twitter API to fetch JSON and display it to the user as a card with access to the original tweet.
- + Integrated Bootstrap library and CSS3 for styling.
- + Deployed using Heroku on a PostgreSQL database.